WEB DEVELOPER

Professional Summary

I aspire to obtain a position of a Web Developer where my 7 years of experience can increase the bottom line. Using HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript and my online marketing skills for the benefit of a top-level company.

Core Qualifications

- Programming Languages/Operating Systems
- Front-end- HTML, JavaScript, CSS, XHTML, DOM, SEO, W3C Compliant, 508 Compliance, Wordpress, Flash, Bootstrap, MVC

Back-end - PHP, C#, ASP.NET

Database-MySQL, MS Access, SQL Server Management StudioOther- Secret Clearance (Archived)Windows, Macintosh, LINUXSoftware ExperienceAdobe Suite, MS Office, Google Analytics, Piwik Web AnalyticsMicrosoft-MS ASP.NET, Visual Studio

Experience

1-800-Flowers.Com, Inc. December 2013 to Current Web Developer Columbus . $\ensuremath{\mathsf{GA}}$

Tasked with re-developing and re-designing existing sites to be better suited for the client Updated content weekly for existing sites
 Converted video's to perform better within said sites Diagnosed and corrected issues arising from the old sites Created and updated
 evaluations to be administered Develop new websites in a SCRUM/AGILE Environment Analyze and report web analytics and trends
 Launched new landing pages and content changes on a continuous deployment cycle Used HTML5 to allow the ability to stream videos
 from a media server Re-developed and Re-designed the front end of the evaluation platform that is viewed by the user Added 508
 Compliance to the evaluation platform front end Streamlined processes to improve efficiency Created and updated help guides to help cross
 train team.

Basf August 2012 to December 2013 Application Technician Tucson , AZ

Diagnosed and corrected issues with various courses housed in the company's LMS Helped grow the department brand with weekly
newsletters seen by up to 500 associates Designed and developed a training course using HTML and JQUERY to better prepare new hires
within the team Redesigned workflow to help speed up the department in their day to day activities Designed new logos in Photoshop for
various corporate events Handled customer issues using Parature ticketing system with speed and efficiency Managed multiple projects
within the department.

Big Sea January 2011 to August 2012 Web Designer/Media Producer Asheville , NC

Created landing sites for many of the company's products using HTML and CSS Increased main site traffic by incorporating land in sites
and using social media Created a Wordpress Blog to facilitate the companies growing brand Edited the theme to fit the companies design
Monitored users and posts to the blog and edited entries Manage the apparel that is sold on website Streamlined apparel to reduce cost on
the company by 15% Vinyl printing experience as well as photography experience Taken photos in a convention type atmosphere and had
success editing in Photoshop Produced laser engraving and embroidery.

Michelle Renee Photography May 2010 to December 2010 Web Master City , STATE

- Conceptualized and developed a site for Michelle Renee Photography Originally developed the site using Wordpress Edited existing Wordpress themes Later built the site from scratch using HTML and CSS.
- Integrated a SEO system to rank the site higher on search engines and increased traffic to the site by 15% and profit grew by 37% Developed a Javascript add-on to display images in a professional manner on the site Created a professional and modern look Created graphics using Photoshop CS4 and Adobe Illustrator Created business card logos using Adobe Illustrator Managed graphics and assets on the server using Adobe Bridge and Dreamweaver.

SAIC July 2010 to December 2010 HTML Support Specialist City , STATE

Resolved errors on SAICs portal Integrated new ASP.NET code with older code to fix errors Worked with HTML heavily in this position
Worked with a ticketing system to help resolve issues Organized the issues to fix them more efficiently and to be better productive to get
more done in a day Troubleshoot errorsand applied fixes.

Genesis Engineering November 2009 to November 2010 Web Master City, STATE

Used HTML and CSS to develop site Integrated SEO capabilities helping to rank site higher on search engines Created a DOM script for
Genesis Engineering which kept cost of the website production down by 10% Designed and established professional grade graphics for
Genesis Engineering Created visually appealing logos that would attract the eye of potential clients Reported 6% business increase on new

clients.

Access On Time June 2009 to September 2009 Web Designer City , $\ensuremath{\mathsf{STATE}}$

Successfully re-designed their existing site Researched CSS to redesign and revitalize their site Integrated a new system of CSS that was not
being used prior to my employment Previous site was faulty and unaesthetic Fixed and redesigned site which successfully increased traffic by
12% Conceptualized new graphics for Access On Time and redesigned existing graphics This obtained new clients for the company and
strengthened the relationships with the old clients.

Education

University of Central Florida December 2010 BA: Digital Media, Digital Interactive Systems City, State Digital Media, Digital Interactive Systems

Skills

ASP.NET, Adobe Suite, Adobe, Dreamweaver, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, AGILE, content, CSS, client, clients, Database, designing, DOM, editing, Flash, Google Analytics, graphics, HTML, HTML5, PHP, JavaScript, JQUERY, laser, LINUX, logos, Macintosh, Access, MS Access, C#, MS Office, Windows, MVC, MySQL, newsletters, search engines, Operating Systems, Photography, processes, profit, Programming, SCRUM, script, SQL Server, Troubleshoot, type, video, Visual Studio, website, websites, website production, workflow, XHTML